(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ライブ後に重大告知あり！
Important announcement after the live!
Starring 星街すいせい
Starring Hoshimachi Suisei
Selfish of a Rough Stone
Hoshimachi Suisei 4th Anniversary
一人一つの存在とは限らない
You're not necessarily limited to a single existence.
Why can't I stop it?
昨日の違う私が違う答え出してたんだろう
A different version of me yesterday must've given a different answer.
Why can't I stop it?
Go as you like, Yes or No
どちらも気分次第
Either one is just a matter of mood.
飽きもしない自分がもっといるの
There are more versions of me that I'll never grow tired of.
この退屈な世界を渡るには
In order to cross this boring world...
力を合わせなきゃダメよ
...we have to join forces.
ほら私とあなたと私なら
See, if it's me, and you, and me...
やがて奇跡が起きちゃって
...then eventually a miracle will happen.
だけど今は 我慢しようか
But for now, shall we hold back?
至福の時さ Step up power
It's a blissful time, step up power!
一日の記憶で一人だと信じ込んで
Convinced that I'm just one person with a single day's memory...
Just can't stop it
真の姿がみんなと違うことを嫌悪して
...loathing that my true form is different from everyone else's.
Go for it, Just stopじゃない
Go for it, it's not a "Just stop."
彷徨わず跳んじゃえば
If you just jump without wandering...
No stop and run, Stopじゃない
No stop and run, it's not a "Stop."
彷徨わず跳んじゃえば
If you just jump without wandering...
本当の自分わかるんだ、でもさ
I understand my true self, but you see...
また聖なる世界夢見てるの
I'm dreaming of a holy world again
美しさはもろいものよ、多分
Beauty is a fragile thing, perhaps
あなたとあなたと私達
You and you and us
無垢なままでいられない
We can't remain innocent
聖なる世界夢見てるの
I'm dreaming of a holy world
白い翼を背負いたいの
I want to carry white wings on my back
でもあなたとあなたと私達
But you and you and us
無垢なままでいられない
We can't remain innocent
この退屈な世界を渡るには
To cross this boring world
力を合わせなきゃだめよ、ほら
We must join forces, look
私とあなたと私なら
If it's me and you and I
やってきた奇跡が起きちゃうね
A miracle will surely happen
だけど今は、我慢しようか、至福の時
But for now, shall we be patient for the blissful moment?
タイミング待ってる
I'm waiting for the timing
いつかどこか、私とあなた
Someday, somewhere, you and I
出会うはずでしょ、明日を奪う
Are supposed to meet, aren't we? Stealing tomorrow
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
皆さん、本日は星街すいせい 4周年LIVEに
Everyone, thank you very much for coming to the
お越しいただき、誠にありがとうございます。
Hoshimachi Suisei 4th Anniversary Live today.
えー、星街すいせい 4周年LIVEで、
Um, please tweet using the hashtag
ぜひハッシュタグをつけてツイートしてください。
for the Hoshimachi Suisei 4th Anniversary Live.
それでは、本日はたくさん歌って参りますので、
Well then, I'll be singing a lot today, so
次のステージへ、そして次の衣装へ、
I'd like to change for the next stage
着替えたいと思います。
and the next outfit.
うんとこしょっと。じゃあ。
Heave-ho. See you then.
U
作詞/作曲 : 常田 大希
Lyrics/Composition: Daiki Tsuneta
La la lai, la la lai
誰も知らない名も無い今を駆け抜けて行くの
Running through a nameless present that no one knows
火に翳し消えて 手を伸ばして
Fading in the flames, reaching out my hand
La la lai, la la lai
君を知りたい 声にならない臆病さを
I want to know you, the wordless cowardice
抱いたまま 迎えようとも
Even if I welcome it while holding onto it
不揃いな感情の火 消えたその時
The fire of uneven emotions, when it went out
世界と逸れてしまったみたいだ
It's as if I got separated from the world
目に映る景色が 哀しく笑うなら
If the scenery in your eyes smiles sadly
火照り詰まる 瞳を閉じてごらん
Try closing your flushed eyes
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ 鼓動鳴る方へさ
Come this way everyone, towards the beating heart
踵打ち鳴らせどうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Stamp your heels, towards where your heart dances
蜃気楼に飛び乗って 逆しまな世界 乗りこなして
Jump on the mirage, master this upside-down world
La la lai, la la lai
止まない愛を知りたい 願う間違い
I want to know the unending love, the wishing mistake
時を超えて 朝から夜まで
Crossing time from morning until night
La la lai, la la lai
君を知りたい 何一つ見逃さぬように
I want to know you, so as not to miss a single thing
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time waits for no one
残酷な運命が 抗えぬ宿命が
Is it cruel fate or irresistible destiny?
考える間も無く押し寄せ 刹那を鳴らして
It rushes in instantly, making a sound in the moment
前が見えなくたって 君を信じてみたいの
Even if I can't see ahead, I want to believe in you
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら
If you take a step without fear...
どうぞどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へ
Please, please, toward the sound of the heartbeat
さあ 踵打ち鳴らせ
Now, stamp your heels
どうぞどうぞ 心の踊る方へ
Please, please, toward the place where the heart dances
さあ 皆さん こちらへ どうぞ鼓動の鳴る方へ
Now everyone, this way, please, toward the sound of the heartbeat
さあ 踵打ち鳴らせ
Now, stamp your heels
どうぞどうぞ 心の踊る方へ
Please, please, toward the place where the heart dances
空を駆け鞠に乗って
Riding on a ball that flies through the sky
始まり得た世界を乗り尽くせ
Ride through the world that could have begun
ラ ナ ナ ナ… 誰も知らない
Ra na na na... That no one knows
名前も無い今を駆け抜けてゆくの
Running through the nameless present
あの三日月へ手を伸ばして
Reach out toward that crescent moon
ラ ナ ナ ナ… 君を知りたい
Ra na na na... I want to know you
声にならない臆病な跡を
The voiceless, cowardly traces
後留めなき迎えようと思う
I intend to welcome them without end
夢ならば覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up
現実なんてさ、鈍いものだ
Reality is such a dull thing
Ah...
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time waits for no one
鏡面の波
Kyōmen no Nami (Mirror's Wave)
ね、むりの手
The hand of sleep
閉じ込められていた熱が
The heat that was trapped
いつぎり輪に
On the waves of time
ただ酔った
Simply floating
その色
That color
行き先を忘れて日々に溶けた
Forgetting the destination, it melted into the days
結び目 呟く
The connection whispers
露受け止める 器 欠けた
The vessel that catches the dew is broken
一欠片探してる
Searching for a broken piece
夕立が
The evening shower
名付けられた世界を剥がした時
When it stripped away the named world
それは涙のように
It is like tears
指の隙間をすり抜けて
Slipping through the fingers
消えて形を変え 繰り返す
Disappearing, changing shape, and repeating
夢だけが私を繋いでいる
Only the dream connects me
夜の中を彷徨っている
Wandering in the night
移ろう季節は忘れ物
The shifting seasons are things left behind
誰かを想う言葉は
Words of thinking of someone
誰かの想いに気付けないまま
While still failing to notice someone's thoughts
きっと鏡のように
Surely like a mirror
失くしたものが全てかな
I wonder if it's all the things lost
完璧な均衡
A perfect equilibrium
永遠の半ば
In the middle of eternity
突き刺す雫
The piercing droplet
揺らめく
Flickers
夜の中を彷徨っている
Wandering in the night
移ろう季節は忘れ物
The shifting seasons are things left behind
夜の中を彷徨っている
Wandering in the night
欠けた一つを探してる
Searching for a missing piece
風が私の声を妨げた時
When the wind obstructed my voice
少しでも迷わないように
So that I won't lose my way even a little
名付けられた世界を…
The named world...
名付けられた世界を剥がした時
When it stripped away the named world
それは涙のように
It is like tears
指の隙間をすり抜けて消えてしまう
Slipping through the fingers and disappearing
鏡面の波
Kyomen no Nami
あぁ 遠く黒い空
Ah, the distant black sky
鼓動は雷鳴を繰り返す
My heartbeat repeats the thunder
嵐が来る前に
Before the storm arrives
今宵はあの歌を授けましょう
Tonight, I shall bestow that song upon you
覚醒
Awakening
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
蘇らせるのさ
I will bring it back to life
愛する君の心
Your beloved heart
体を脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off your body
今我に返る時
Now is the time to come back to your senses
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ 覚醒
Amare dirahi yumaki, Awakening
目をつむって
Close your eyes
風を掬って
Scoop up the wind
身を溶かして
Melt your body
鐘を鳴らして
Ring the bell
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ 覚醒
Amare dirahi yumaki, Awakening
雷鳴は
The thunderclaps
何千とうぶ声をあげる
Cries out thousands of times
歌声さ
The voice of a song
山を越えて
Over the mountains
飛び出せ
Take off!
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
アマレ ディラヒ ユマキ ガシャラ
Amare dirahi yumaki gashala
マハリ ユワレ ガイェ サバナレ
Mahari yuware gaye sabanare
Ready Steady
作詞：q*Left / 作曲：Giga
Lyrics: q*Left / Composition: Giga
凡そ邪魔　物足りなさは消えちゃったし
Mostly a nuisance, the feeling of lack has vanished
あり余って笑っちゃうくらい
To the point where I'm laughing because there's so much
獲物はないなんて言ったってしょうがないし
It's no use saying there's no prey
お手上げでハイファイブ
Hands up for a high five
燃えりゃええ　後に続いたってつまんねえ
Just burn it up, it's boring to follow behind
夢を語れ　俺がこの街のスタンダーダー
Talk about your dreams, I'm the standard-setter in this city
まだ見たい退屈だけなんてNO 嘘です
I still want to see, just boredom is a NO, I'm lying
そろそろマイク頂戴
Give me the mic soon
さよなら　もう後戻りもできないくらい
Goodbye, so far that I can't turn back
遠くに隠させてもらう
I'll hide away far away
まだまだ嵌まっていきたい　なんかまるで恋してるみたい
I want to keep falling for it, it feels just like being in love
好きになっちゃった　うっせぇな
I've fallen for you, shut up
ならこのまま　君を連れて望むなら
Then just like this, if you want me to take you along
どこまでも演じたいわ
I want to play the part forever
欲しがってばかりで結構結構
Just wanting more and more is fine, fine
もし叶うなら　この先の未来を知りたい
If it comes true, I want to know the future ahead
行きたい
I want to go
Ready Steady
ほんのちょっとだけなら　無茶だってしちゃいたいし
If it's just a little bit, I want to do something reckless
この世のすべてで笑っちゃうくらい
To the point of laughing at everything in this world
とはいえがったって馬鹿じゃどうしようもないし
Even so, if you're a fool who complains, there's no helping it
媚び跳ねてハイファイブ
Spurning flattery for a high five
ねえ少しはこっち向いたらどう？
Hey, why don't you look this way for a bit?
今更嵌まらしたいだけ
I just want to get you hooked now
誰もが羨む今宵トラックとリリックで
With tonight's tracks and lyrics that everyone envies
見せていくからリテイクはしないで
I'll show you, so please don't retake
ならこのまま　君を連れて望むなら
Then just like this, if you want me to take you along
どこまでも演じたいわ
I want to play the part forever
ないものねだりなら結構結構
If it's asking for the impossible, that's fine, fine
はやく宵明けって　朝焼けに誓う
Swear to the sunrise that the dawn will come soon
煽れ煽れ熱の叫べ
Stir it up, stir it up, scream with heat
この声をきいて尊ぶ音に
Hear this voice, in the sound I revere
音に狂え
Go crazy for the sound
I want more
Are you Ready?
"Are you Ready?"
どこまでも演じたいわ
I want to play the part forever
欲しがってばかりで結構結構
Just wanting more and more is fine, fine
もし叶うなら　この先の未来を知りたい
If it comes true, I want to know the future ahead
行きたい
I want to go
Ready Steady
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
ハローハロー！
Hello hello!
ハロー、エブリワン！
Hello, everyone!
ハロー、エブリワン！楽しんでるー！？
Hello, everyone! Are you having fun!?
やったー！すごーい！カリオペ！
Yay! Amazing! Calliope!
本当に嬉しい！嬉しいです、よかった！
I'm really happy! I'm happy, I'm glad!
やったー、嬉しい！
Yay, I'm happy!
おめでとう！3D！
Congratulations on the 3D!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
こちらこそ！なんか、えっと、
Same here! Well, um,
4周年記念と誕生日すごいおめでとうございます！
Congratulations on your 4th anniversary and birthday!
やったー！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
めっちゃめっちゃワクワクしてる、本当にね。
I'm really, really excited, honestly.
ワクワクワクワクしてる。やったー！
I'm so excited. Yay!
おカリオペの動きが、もうなんか、パワフル、本当に。
Calliope's movements are just so powerful, really.
そうね。
Right.
イェーイ！すごい！
Yay! Amazing!
え、あの、Twitterのナンバー2トレンド！
Uh, um, number 2 trending on Twitter!
ナンバー2トレンド！すごい！
Number 2 trending! Amazing!
やったー！めっちゃありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
なんか今日、カリオペを呼びたいと思って、お呼びさせていただきまして。
I wanted to invite Calliope today, so I did.
もうね、過密なスケジュールの中来ていただきまして、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming despite your packed schedule.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
なんか、すごい光栄です。
I'm so honored.
ずっと一緒に3Dで歌いたかったから、めっちゃ嬉しいです。
I've always wanted to sing in 3D together, so I'm very happy.
私も嬉しい！イェーイ！
I'm happy too! Yay!
本当に髪とかが、すごく...
Really, your hair and everything is just so...
そうね
Right
ぴったりね
They match perfectly
ね、私ホワイト、あなたブラック
Right? I'm white, you're black
いいね
Nice
最高、マジで
The best, seriously
最高
The best
最高、マジで
The best, seriously
Yeah, check it out! Check it out, everyone!
Ready Steady, めっちゃ楽しかった
Ready Steady was so much fun
やった、楽しかった！よかった
Yeah, it was fun! I'm glad
私もね、Ready Steadyね、これを絶対カリオペと歌いたいと思って
I really wanted to sing Ready Steady with Calliope
そうね。ラップの部分、いっぱい練習してた私
Yeah. I practiced the rap part a lot
ありがとう！いや、難しいから、日本語のラップ
Thank you! I mean, Japanese rap is hard
でもね、もう見事にやってくれましたよ
But you did it perfectly!
ああ、ありがとうございます。本当に頑張りました
Ah, thank you so much. I really did my best
イェーイ！もう皆さんいかがでしたか？ちょっとコメント読んでいきましょう
Yeah! How was it for everyone? Let's read some comments
おっ、いい雰囲気になってるね。あっ、ありがとう！
Oh, "the atmosphere is great". Ah, thank you!
Hello!
Hello everybody!
Hello hello! Thank you!
プリキュア並みだって！やったー！確かに
They say it's like PreCure! Yay! True
ブラックとホワイトやん
Black and white
そうね、ありがとう！
Yeah, thank you!
ラップ良かったって、日本語上手だって
They say the rap was good, and your Japanese is great
え、マジか？信じられないけど、本当に嬉しいです。マジ。ありがとう！
Wait, really? I can't believe it, but I'm really happy. Seriously. Thank you!
じゃあね、次
Well then, the next...
次の曲はね...
The next song is...
めっちゃ特別な曲です
It's a very special song
Yes, めっちゃめちゃスペシャルな曲です
Yes, a very, very special song
Yes, a new song. 新曲
Yes, a new song. New song
そう、me and すいせい先輩...
Yes, me and Suisei-senpai...
新曲！！！
New song!!!
二人のデュエット新曲が出ますよ！
Our new duet song is coming out!
Yes, let's do it!
ということでね、これから歌って参りたいと思いますんで皆さん
So, we're going to sing it now for everyone
ちょっ緊張するな、初披露
I'm a bit nervous... the first performance
そうね。私もめっちゃ緊張してるけど、まあ頑張りましょうね
Yeah. I'm really nervous too, but let's do our best
頑張りましょう！
Let's do our best!
Let's do it!
それでは聴いてください
Please listen
Wicked
あんも　欲しもないや
I don't want anything anymore
アテンド　Oh, my liar
Attend Oh, my liar
High & Low　世界を獲りたいね
High & Low, I want to take over the world
勝ち逃げね　今宵は悪のグラン
Winning and running away, tonight is the evil grand [prix]
お門違いな神話は　説教とか勘弁ですわ
Misplaced myths, please spare me the preaching
アシスタントだよ　うるさいなぁ
I'm the assistant, shut up
それって常識ですよ　とか　バカバカしいな
"That's common sense" and all that is ridiculous
前代未聞の　名を作ってだってば
I told you, I'm making a name that's unheard of
Bring you to high span!
Born to be wicked
We just gonna make it
穿ち穿たれて Love it
Piercing and being pierced, love it
歌え今
Sing now
Way a a ah!
己の善と正当　戦うの
Fight with your own goodness and justice
I just gonna make it
Nobody catches me
君と未来のため
For you and the future
見つけていこうんだよ
Let's go find it
I shiny shiny star　届きそうさ
I'm a shiny shiny star, I'm about to reach it
Right now, it's a world where you get what you give
And I'm a girl of a whole lot of adjectives
A couple might say stubborn, rude, hearts please
And the crazy to praise me with secret sleevies, gods please
I came through to get a lot
I'm standing here with Suisei burning hot
Shining stars, bizarre, you can see the scars
Hit the grind, now we shiny, you can see how far we done came
Shame, it's an enormous game, some fun, first fame, second we ain't done
Because we living in the moment and we own it, okay
We done prayed for the weight of an outshining the sun
Damn, already gone give it a try
Saturation and run
Right now by, you can't deny me
You been sleeping, come get a grip
You can't stop dreaming
Born to be wicked
We just gonna make it
穿ち穿たれて Love it
Piercing and being pierced, love it
歌え今　Way a a ah!
Sing now, Way a a ah!
己の善と正当　戦うの
Fight with your own goodness and justice
とても不思議ね
It's very mysterious
君といるときだけ
Only when I'm with you
胸撫で下ろせるの
I can breathe a sigh of relief
Cuz you check out the standard with me baby
他の誰も知らない　私見せたり
Showing you a side of me no one else knows
時が止まれば　とか考えていたり
Thinking things like "if only time would stop"
恋い焦がれた　夢の場所へ
To the place of dreams I've longed for
来たのよ long long way
I've come a long, long way
Born to be wicked
We just gonna make it
生み出せば　次のレベル
If we create it, it's the next level
近づいたら　Way a a ah!
If we get closer, Way a a ah!
己のものさして　続けるの
Measuring by your own standards and continuing
知るたび得て
Gaining every time I learn
優しさ故
Because of kindness
それぞれの幸せ
Each person's happiness
皆わかってくんたよ
Everyone is starting to understand
Just moving moving go
そんな運命だ
That's just fate
Born to be wicked and we in the black
Whether angels or devils it's do or die
No cap, let's keep the sound on top, from the back set what we got
Born to be wicked and we in the black
If you still ain't found that eternal sky
止まってんじゃねーよ
Don't you stop
We'll find a way out
Moving moving on ya
季節は次々死んでいく
Seasons Die One After Another
作詞・作曲：秋田 ひろむ
Lyrics/Composition: Hiromu Akita
季節は次々死んでいく
Seasons die one after another,
絶命の声が風になる
and the voices of death turn into the wind.
色めく街の酔えない男
A man who can't get drunk in the colorful city,
月を見上げるのはここじゃ不粋
looking up at the moon is unrefined here.
泥に足もつれる生活に
In a life where feet get tangled in the mud,
雨はアルコールの味がした
the rain tasted like alcohol.
アパシーな目で彷徨う街で
In the city wandering with apathetic eyes,
挙動不審のイノセント 駅前で
suspiciously behaving innocents in front of the station.
僕が僕と呼ぶには不確かな
It's too uncertain for me to call myself "me",
半透明な影が生きてる風だ
it's like a semi-transparent shadow is alive.
雨に歌えば雲は割れるか
If I sing in the rain, will the clouds part?
賑やかな夏の干涸びた命だ
It's a parched life in a boisterous summer.
拝啓 忌まわしき過去に告ぐ 絶縁の詩
Dearly, to my detestable past, a poem of severance.
最低な日々の最悪な夢の残骸を 捨てては行けず
Unable to throw away the wreckage of the worst dreams from my worst days.
ここで生きてようと 後生花は咲き
Though I try to live here, flowers after death bloom,
君に伝う 変遷の詩
and a poem of transition reaches you.
苦にまみれて 嘆き悲しみ
Covered in bitterness, grieving and sorrowful,
それでも 途絶えぬ歌に
even so, in an unending song,
陽は射さずとも
even if the sun does not shine.
明日は次々死んでいく
Tomorrows die one after another,
急いでも追いつけず過去になる
they become the past even if you hurry to catch up.
生き急げ僕ら 灯る火は切な
Live fast, we are; the lit fire is fleeting,
生きる意味などは後からつく
the meaning of life will come later.
君が君でいるには不確かな
It's too uncertain for you to be "you",
不安定な自我が君を嫌おうと
even if your unstable ego hates you.
せめて歌えば闇は晴れるか
If I at least sing, will the darkness clear?
根腐れた夢に預けた命だ
It's a life entrusted to a root-rotted dream.
拝啓 忌まわしき過去に告ぐ 絶縁の詩
Dearly, to my detestable past, a poem of severance.
最低な日々の最悪な夢の残骸を 捨てては行けず
Unable to throw away the wreckage of the worst dreams from my worst days.
ここで生きてようと 後生花は咲き
Though I try to live here, flowers after death bloom,
君に伝う 変遷の詩
and a poem of transition reaches you.
苦にまみれて 嘆き悲しみ
Covered in bitterness, grieving and sorrowful,
それでも 途絶えぬ歌に
even so, in an unending song,
陽は射さずとも
even if the sun does not shine.
疲れた顔に足をひきずって
Dragging my feet with a tired face,
照り返す夕日に顔をしかめて
grimacing at the reflecting sunset.
行こうか戻ろうか悩みはするけど
I worry whether to go or to go back,
しばらくすれば歩き出す背中
but after a while, my back starts walking again.
そうだ 行かねばならぬ
That's right, I must go.
何はなくとも生きてゆくのだ
I will keep on living, no matter what.
僕らは どうせ拾った命だ
We are, after all, lives that were picked up,
ここに置いていくよ なけなしの...
I'll leave it here, my meager...
拝啓 忌まわしき 過去に告ぐ...
Dearly, to my detestable past...
...想うばかりの詩
...only a poem of thoughts.
最低な日々が
The lowest of days,
最悪な夢が
the worst of dreams,
始まりだったと思えば
when I think they were the beginning,
随分遠くだ
they seem quite far away.
どうせ 砂は散り
Anyway, the sand scatters,
輪廻の輪に
into the wheel of reincarnation,
還る命
lives return.
苦悩にまみれて
Covered in suffering,
嘆き悲しみ
grieving and sorrowing,
それでも
even so,
絶えぬ歌に
in the unending song,
陽は射さずとも
even if the sun doesn't shine.
季節は次々死んでいく
The seasons die one after another.
今夜はから騒ぎ / 作詞・作曲：椎名林檎
Much Ado About Tonight / Lyrics & Composition: Shiina Ringo
チュー・ル・チュー・ル...
Chu ru chu ru...
...満ち来は来候て満ちて
...it rises and falls, then rises again.
おきっと仕度時よ
Surely it's time to prepare.
御大人前の貸借
Lending and borrowing like an adult.
足下を洗うべきよ
You should wash your feet.
御人好味の売買
Buying and selling like a good person.
まなじりの真相は
The truth in the corner of the eye
語るまじよなずな
must not be spoken, shepherd's purse.
当然の報いだよ
It's a natural consequence.
徒に其処等へ咲いて
Blooming there in vain.
添え得た罰だよ
It's a punishment that came along.
御時限下の売買
Buying and selling under the time limit.
裏切りの衝動は
The impulse of betrayal
秋の夜の恋煩い
is the love-sickness of an autumn night.
浮かばれるか沈むか
Will I float or sink?
Amuckな渡御Harbor
An amuck procession harbor.
だから悩ませられてまう
That's why I end up being troubled.
追息吐息
Gasping for breath.
笑顔が眩しいね
Your smile is radiant.
目醒めて御覚め
Wake up and be aware.
泡を吹くじゃ泡を吹かす
If I froth at the mouth, I'll make you froth.
御博打思わし
Suggesting a gamble.
あたふたもぬけの殻は
In a fluster, the empty shell is...
計りの非情
...measuring ruthlessness.
終わり行く大演劇(スマイ)は
The ending grand drama (smile) is...
有難り
...a grateful gathering.
あの始まって愚痴も用なし
Since it started, there's no use for complaints.
寝たの目算の
Calculating while asleep.
チュー・ル・チュー・ル...
Chu ru chu ru...
...満ち来は来候て満ちて
...it rises and falls, then rises again.
チュー・ル・チュー・ル...
Chu ru chu ru...
...満ち来は来候て満ちて
...it rises and falls, then rises again.
皆さん 行きますよー！
Everyone, here we go!
エゴロック / 作詞・作曲：すりぃ
Ego Rock / Lyrics & Composition: Surii
その桁外れに I need you 巷に溢れるロイド
In that extraordinary way, I need you.
The city's overflowing with 'roids.
あたかもネットのシャレコウベ 鳴らせディストーション
Like a skull on the net,
crank up the distortion.
継ぎ接ぎ刃のサムライが 見だれる散弾銃
The samurai with the patched blade,
a chaotic shotgun.
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか ほら てんてこへんてこまいまい
Shall we dance to the history of tragedy?
See, we're all in a fluster.
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め四十五度ナンセンス
My heart is Ego Rock,
a forty-five-degree tilt of nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crush the know-how,
and say bye-bye-bye to the rut tomorrow.
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning figure,
a nauseating sky pattern.
アイアイアイ
Ai ai ai.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も虚 目を塞ぐふり
A rain of cynical gazes,
pretending to close my hollow eyes today too.
おちゃらけ集まれ I need you 巷にあふれるロイド
Gather 'round, you jesters, I need you.
'Roids overflowing the streets.
あの子も流行りのインスタンス 撒き散らす ID
That kid's a trendy instance too,
scattering their ID.
うだつが上がらぬサムライが 未来をアイコか
The samurai who can't get ahead,
will the future be a draw?
無残な歴史で歌おうよ ほら ちゃんちゃらなんちゃらまいまい
Let's sing to the cruel history.
Look, it's all nonsense.
僕の心で生きようか 真夏のホットなミュージック
Shall we live in my heart?
Hot midsummer music.
ハウツー砕いてまるかいて 明日もわははは
Crush the how-to,
draw a circle, and laugh tomorrow too.
バイバイバイ
Bye-bye-bye.
洒落臭さも癖になる はみ出し者だろう
Even the cheekiness becomes a habit.
You're an outcast, right?
アイアイアイ
Ai ai ai.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も虚 目を開くふり
A rain of cynical gazes,
pretending to open my hollow eyes today too.
透明な感情は 染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions just get stained.
だから見て見ぬふりする奴らを押し出せ
So push out those who pretend not to see.
人生掛けても負けそうです 勝ち負けとりまナンセンス
Likely to lose even with my life on the line.
Winning or losing is nonsense for now.
ビートを砕いて常識を 未来にセイグッバイ
Crush the beat and say goodbye
to common sense in the future.
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め四十五度ナンセンス
My heart is Ego Rock,
a forty-five-degree tilt of nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crush the know-how,
and say bye-bye-bye to the rut tomorrow.
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning figure,
a nauseating sky pattern.
アイアイアイ
Ai ai ai.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も虚 目を塞ぐふり
A rain of cynical gazes,
pretending to close my hollow eyes today too.
1 2 3 Fuck you!
はい！ということで皆さん！
Hi! So, everyone!
こんにちはー！
Hello!
わーい！
Yay!
はい、えーっと、ここまで5曲歌わせていただきました。
Yes, um, I've sung five songs so far.
カリオペとの2曲と、
The two with Calliope, and...
あ、6曲だった。
Oh, it was six.
最初の一曲と…
With the first song and...
あ、全然違った。えーっと…
Oh, that's completely wrong. Um...
あ、9曲歌ってました。
Oh, I've sung nine songs.
いや、頭がバグってました。
Man, my head was bugged.
皆さんこんにちはー！
Hello, everyone!
はい、えーっと、えーっとですね。
Yes, um, so anyway...
いや、3連続で、いや4連続か。
No, three in a row—no, it was four.
カリオペとの最後、Wickedから4連続で歌わせていただきまして。
I've sung four in a row since the last one
with Calliope, Wicked.
えっと、どうでしたか？
Um, how was it?
えっ、どうでしたか？
How was it?
すいちゃん、記憶がやばい。
Suichan's memory is shot.
ちょっとね、緊張してるかもしれない。
I might be a little nervous.
何かが起こるかもしれないと思って、
Thinking something might happen,
今、緊張で震えてるかもしれない。
I might be shaking with nerves right now.
はい、えーっと、ということでね。
Yes, um, so anyway.
あ、トレンド1位とかもありがとうございます。
Oh, and thank you for getting us to #1 on trending.
えっと、この衣装！すごいでしょ！
Um, this outfit! It's amazing, right?
この衣装！すごいでしょ！
This outfit! It's amazing, right?
ほらー！
Look!
新衣装作ってもらいました。およさんに。イェーイ。
I had a new outfit made for me. By Oyo-san. Yay.
いいカメラでの新衣装。後ろとかも。
The new outfit on a good camera. Even the back.
ほら、どうですか？
See, how is it?
本邦初公開の後ろ姿です。
This is the first time the back has been shown.
なんか緊張してて、あの、新衣装だっていうことも忘れてました。
I was so nervous that I even forgot
it was a new outfit.
いや、あるよね。
No, it happens, right?
よし、おめでとう！
Alright, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、えーっと、実はこの衣装なんですけど、
Yes, um, actually, for this outfit,
ジャケットがありますよね。
there's a jacket.
ジャケット！
Jacket!
ジャケット見たい？
Want to see the jacket?
ジャケットもあるよ。
There's a jacket too.
ジャケット見たいよね？
You want to see the jacket, right?
じゃあ、ちょっと今からマジックするんで、
Alright, I'm going to do some magic now,
行きますよ。
so here we go.
じゃあカメラさん、
Okay, Mr. Cameraman,
行きますよー！
here we go!
はい！
Yes!
お、しょいのはい！
Heave-ho!
はい！
Yes!
え、どうですか？はいはいはいはいはい。
Eh, how is it? Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
はい足。これ足ね。
Yes, legs. These are my legs.
はい、はい、はい、はい、はい...
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes...
あ、これ、この後ろ...
Oh, this, the back...
ジャケットのこの後ろのさ、オレンジ、本邦初公開。
This orange part on the back of the jacket, shown for the first time.
やったー！
Yay!
口に当たっちゃった、マイクが。あはははは。
The mic hit my mouth! Haha.
えー、はい。運営さんを脅して作らせました。
Um, yes. I threatened the staff into making this.
可愛い衣装です。
It's a cute outfit.
やったー！
Yay!
いや、あの、ちょっと気づいた方もいるかもしれないんですけど、
Well, some of you might have noticed,
今回はね、ロック調の曲をたくさん選曲させていただいておりまして、
but this time I've selected many rock-style songs,
で、ロック調の曲にすごい合う衣装なんじゃないかなと思っております。
so I thought this outfit would really suit rock songs.
ではね、次の曲いきたいんですけど、
Now, I want to go to the next song,
まずちょっとここじゃなくて、向こうで歌うんで、ちょっと向こうに戻りたいと思います。
but I'll be singing it over there, so I'm going to head back there.
それじゃ、戻りますよ。今から。
Well then, I'm heading back now.
よし、はい！
Alright, yes!
はい、後ろ向いた！はい、走ってます！
Yes, turned around! Yes, I'm running!
私は...！
I am...!
みんなー！はいみんな！
Everyone! Hi everyone!
すいちゃんだよー。花道を、
It's Sui-chan. Along the runway,
花道を歩いています、すいちゃん。
Sui-chan is walking the runway.
はい、戻ってきたー！
Yes, I'm back!
はい戻ってきた！はい戻ってきた！
Yes, I'm back! Yes, I'm back!
ふー。ということでね、このメインステージに戻ってきたということで、
Phew. And so, now that I'm back on this main stage,
そろそろみんなも次の曲聴きたいよね？
everyone wants to hear the next song soon, right?
次はなんじゃろな？
What's next?
あ、気づいたら45分経ってる。
Oh, I realized 45 minutes have passed.
はい。では行きますよ。
Alright. Here we go.
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。
Well then, please listen to the next song.
駆けろ。
Kakero.
駆けろ
作詞・作曲：みきとP
Kakero (Run)
Lyrics & Composition: Mikito-P
本音も
Both true feelings
建前も
and pretenses
駆け引き上手な大人
Adults good at maneuvering
ダメだね
It's no good
そんな言葉信じられない
I can't believe those words
できない
I can't
べたべた掻き消して
Scrawling and erasing
進化し続けるって蜘蛛の字
Keep on evolving like a spider
吐いて
Exhaling
人肌の温もり
the warmth of human skin
ねぇ このままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, this world is an unending rain
もう悲しくない
It's not sad anymore,
人になれる生き物だから
because we are creatures who can become human
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だっけ
Right, what page was it of our blank youth?
今君に会いたいと
Now I want to see you,
涙込み上げる
tears welling up
ふんばり
Struggling
蹴ったり
and kicking,
注意散漫人生の天気だ
the weather of a distracted life
新しい
A new era,
時代を乗りこなしていくんだ
I'm going to master it
透明で 鮮明で
Transparent and vivid,
叫び声上げる前乗り気
in a mood to shout out
手を挙げ
Raising my hand,
失敗しては学んでいく
learning from failures
もうこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Already this world is an unending rain
愛するしかない それしかない
All I can do is love, that's all,
非情じゃないから
because it's not heartless
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だっけ
Right, what page was it of our blank youth?
忘れ物思い出せないまま
Without being able to remember what was left,
忘れそう
likely to forget
このままじゃ
At this rate...
風の形見えない
The shape of the wind is invisible
見えないよあなたが
I can't see you
あなただって同じ
You're the same,
じっとなんてしてられない
can't just stay still
動き出すよ
Starting to move,
この身賭けて
betting this body
交差ないよ
No intersection,
泣いたってしょうがないさ
it's no use crying
ねぇ このままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, this world is an unending rain
もう悲しくない
It's not sad anymore,
人になれる生き物だから
because we are creatures who can become human
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だっけ
Right, what page was it of our blank youth?
今君に会いたいと
Now I want to see you,
涙こらえて
holding back tears
さよならだ さよならなんだって認めたくないけど
It's goodbye, I don't want to admit it's goodbye,
雨上がりのこの世界が眩しいから
because this world after the rain is dazzling
もう帰らない 振り返らない
No longer returning, not looking back,
思い出とともに
along with memories
風に煽られ
...buffeted by the wind
そしてまた君に会いたいと願い
and wishing to meet you again
駆けてゆく
I'll run on
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで
作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
Celestial Sphere, Comet Striding Through the Night
Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
明かりが一つ灯った 灯った
A single light turned on, turned on
天を彩った描写が綺麗だ
The depiction that colored the sky is beautiful
僕の吐いた白い息のように
Like the white breath I exhaled
消してしまえたらな
If only I could make it disappear
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Stifled and sunk deep
泣き声さえ聞こえているから
Because even the sound of crying can be heard
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
The anxiety and pain that pierced you
僕の青色で 塗りつぶして
Painting over them with my blue
全部涙になって
Turning all into tears
星の海を流れていった
They flowed through the sea of stars
果てしない闇の中に
In the endless darkness
そっと這わせたら ほらほら
If you let them crawl gently, see, see
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew over my head
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
Staining the night sky where no one is
深く寝静まった街の中へ
Into the city that has fallen into a deep sleep
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that rains down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew in an arc again
思考を晴らして
Clearing the mind
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we could meet again someday
星が降った後の街僕はまだ
In the city after the stars fell, I'm still...
黒く澄んだランドの空を
The black, clear sky of the land
箒星が彩るように
Like a comet coloring it
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
The anxiety and pain that pierced you
僕の青色で塗りつぶして
Painting over them with my blue
君の涙をそっと
Gently taking your tears
星の海に流し込むんだ
And pouring them into the sea of stars
尾を引いたその光が
That light trailing behind
誰かをまた救うから
Will save someone again
彗星が僕らの頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew over our heads
この空を全部君にあげる
I'll give this entire sky to you
言えなかった言葉の尾を引いて
Trailing the words I couldn't say
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that rains down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew in an arc again
街の喧騒を背負い去るように
As if carrying away the city's hustle and bustle
君とまた会えるなら僕はほら
If I can meet you again, look, I...
星の名前を一つ受け止めよう
Will catch the name of a star
悲しみが溢れそうになること
Even if sadness seems like it's about to overflow
地球で離れ離れでも
Even if we're far apart on Earth
僕らは繋がっているから
Because we are connected
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew over my head
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
Staining the night sky where no one is
深く寝静まった街の中へ
Into the city that has fallen into a deep sleep
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sadness is it that rains down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The stars flew in an arc again
思考を晴らして
Clearing the mind
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we could meet again someday
星が降った後の街僕はもうずっと
In the city after the stars fell, I've always...
君の行方を探してた
Been searching for your whereabouts
画面の向こうのそのまた向こうで
Beyond the screen, and even further beyond that,
放たれた言葉たち
the words that have been unleashed.
殴っても痛まない透明な拳
Transparent fists that don't hurt even when they strike.
満天の星のように散らばっている
Scattered like a sky full of stars,
ガラスの破片の上を
above the shards of glass,
裸足で歩くような痛みだ
it's a pain like walking barefoot.
僕はずっと苦しかったんだ
I've been suffering all this time.
さあ僕にとって正解なんてどうだっていい
Now, for me, I don't care what the "correct answer" is.
「正解」なんてどうだっていい
"Correct answer" doesn't matter.
この生が正しいか間違いか自分で決めるから
Whether this life is right or wrong, I'll decide for myself.
その手に抱えた
In your hands,
大層なテンプレート 打ち砕いて
smash that grand template you hold.
鏡に映った僕の色は全部
All the colors of me reflected in the mirror
僕のためにあったのに
were supposed to be for me.
気づいたらこの手を離れていた
But before I knew it, they'd left my hands.
名前も顔も隠したアノニマスに
To an Anonymous who's hidden both name and face,
僕の何がわかるの？
what do you know about me?
輪郭さえぼやけそうな痛みも
Even the pain that makes my silhouette blur,
僕の全部、取り返さなくちゃ
I have to take it all back, everything that's mine.
何度遮ったってうるさいほどに鳴るノイズが
No matter how many times I block it out, the noise that rings out so loud it's annoying,
好き放題僕をカテゴリーの檻に縛っても
even if it binds me in a cage of categories as it pleases,
この声の正体
the true identity of this voice...
名前をつけるのは自分だけだろう？
I'm the only one who can name it, right?
もう僕は祈らない
I won't pray anymore.
この街の頭上を
Above the head of this city,
降り注いだ慈愛を仰ぎはしない
I won't look up at the pouring affection.
僕のこの痛みも姿形も
My pain, my appearance, my form,
誰に決められることもない
no one can decide those for me.
さあ僕にとって正解なんてどうだっていい
Now, for me, I don't care what the "correct answer" is.
「正解」なんてどうだっていい
"Correct answer" doesn't matter.
この生が正しいか間違いか自分で決めるから
Whether this life is right or wrong, I'll decide for myself.
あの一等星の輝きにも
Even in the radiance of that first-magnitude star,
幸福が蔓延る理想郷にも
even in a utopia where happiness flourishes,
届かなくたって構わない
I don't mind if I don't reach them.
僕以外、何も要らない
I don't need anything but myself.
星街すいせいニューシングル「TEMPLATE」
Hoshimachi Suisei's new single, "TEMPLATE".
「天球、彗星は夜を跨いで」を手掛けたキタニタツヤさんに書き下ろしてもらいました！
It was written by Tatsuya Kitani, who also worked on "Tenkyu, Suisei wa Yoru wo Mataide"!
この後24時から各音楽配信サービスにて配信開始となります！
Distribution will start on various music streaming services from midnight tonight!
先ほど披露したカリオペとのデュエット曲「Wicked」もカップリング曲として一緒に配信されますよ！
The duet "Wicked" with Calliope, which we just performed, will also be released together as a coupling track!
そしてこの後「TEMPLATE」のMVがすいせいチャンネルで投稿されるので、ぜひ見てください！
And the music video for "TEMPLATE" will be posted on the Suisei Channel right after this, so please check it out!
そして！
And!
なんと「TEMPLATE」が「太鼓の達人プラス」にて最速無料配信されます！
Believe it or not, "TEMPLATE" will be available for free on "Taiko no Tatsujin Plus" starting immediately!
3月31日の22時から「Prism Melody」と同時配信となりますので、皆さんぜひ遊んでみてください！
It will be released simultaneously with "Prism Melody" from 22:00 on March 31st, so please give it a try!
さらに、誕生日と活動4周年を記念した記念グッズの発売も決定しました！
Furthermore, we've decided to release commemorative goods to celebrate my birthday and 4th anniversary!
グッズはアクリルパネル、キャップ、サーモタンブラー、スマホリングの4種類となっています！
The goods consist of four types: acrylic panel, cap, thermo tumbler, and smartphone ring!
この4つがセットになった「フルセット」もございます！
There's also a "Full Set" containing all four items!
フルセットには箔押しサイン入りのポストカードが付いてくる豪華仕様です！
The full set is a luxurious version that comes with a foil-stamped signed postcard!
この後22時から販売開始となりますので、チェックよろしくお願いします！
Sales start at 22:00 after this, so please check it out!
あ！みんなー！
Ah! Everyone!
や、どうだったライブ？
So, how was the live?
あの、あれだね。告知がすごく盛りだくさんでしたね。
Um, there were so many announcements, weren't there?
え、なんと最後にもう一つあります。
And, there's one more thing at the very end.
な、なにかしら？なにかしら？まだあるの？
W-what could it be? What could it be? Is there still more?
じゃあ、えー、この動画を流して、今日のライブは終わりといたします。
So, um, I'll end today's live by playing this video.
では、動画、どうぞ！
So, please watch the video!
MIDNIGHT GRAND ORCHESTRA
星街すいせい & TAKU INOUE New Music Project 『Midnight Grand Orchestra』
Hoshimachi Suisei & TAKU INOUE New Music Project "Midnight Grand Orchestra"
To Be Announced 2022.04.06